

Senior Software Engineer seeking roles in Software Development, Application Programming, Requirement Gathering, Project Management, Continuous Integration, System Analysis, Technical Architecture, HTML, CSS, Core Java, Javascript, Mongo DB



Total Experience: 9 Year(s) 0 Month(s) Current Designation: Senior Java Developer

Current Company: SLK Software Services Notice Period: 2 Months

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Electronics/Telecommunication] Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Ernakulam, Kozhikode

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: HTML,CSS,Core Java,Javascript,Java 8,Spring Mvc,Spring Batch,Spring Framework,Angularjs,MySQL,MS

SQL Server, Bootstrap, Oracle Application Framework, Oracle Apex, Oracle Apps Technical

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 20-Jan-21 Last Modified: 20-Jan-21

Summary

8.6 years of overall work experience in the software industry.

Proficiency in Java, Angular JS, Javascript, Webservices, Maven, SQL and Unix.

2+ years of experience in working as Oracle Technical consultant in

development, implementation and maintenance of Oracle E-business Suite (R12) applications.

Good knowledge in Oracle apps Procure to Pay cycle (R12), system admin module,

Purchasing module, iProcurement, Contracts and Sourcing module.

Experience in OAF, WebADI, APEX technologies

Experience in Java API integration (Web services- SOAP, REST), Desktop and Web applications.

Experience with using Apache Tomcat Server.

Experience with databases like Oracle, MS SQL.

Experience in client side technologies such as HTML, CSS, JQuery, AJAX, JSON.

Expertise on Core Java Technologies like Multithreading, Collections and Exception

Handling mechanisms.

Excellent communication skills, team playing spirit and strong analytical &

problem-solving abilities

Work Experience

SLK Software Services as Senior Java Developer

Oct 2017 to Till Date

Project Title NCC Costing Customization

Company SLK software services Pvt.Ltd.,Bangalore

Client NCC(National concrete cement), Bahrain

Period Feb 20 To March 2020

Part of a 3 members technical team and played main role in the

Description and Job

development and enhancement of R12.1.3 EBS application

Maintenance and enhancements to existing EBS application.

Summary Develop OAF screens for searching BOM and update cost for selected

BOM.

Develop estimates for enhancements and bug fixes. Participate in design reviews and discussions. Create User guide and unit test documents . Technologies used OAF,PL/SQL

Role Senior Software Engineer.

UST Global as Technical Consultant Sep 2015 to Oct 2017

Project Title SSS PO Development Support Project

Company UST-Global-Trivandrum

Client GE-Corporate

Period SEP 2015 To Oct 2017

Analyzing new enhancements/issues reported by business

Description and Job

(Purchasing Module)

Proposing Solutions and preparing estimate

Summary Worked on Requisition, Purchase Order, Receipt, iSupplier and

iProcurement, Contracts and Sourcing modules

Developing Solutions (using OAF & APEX technologies)

Experience on OA page extension - (EO, VO, CO), OA

personalization

Developed custom APEX applications as per the business needs

Preparing Test data and coordinating testing with business

Module Design Documentation and providing KT to support team

Technologies used OAF, APEX, JavaScript, AJAX, PL/SQL

Role Technical Consultant

Gapblue Software Labs Pvt Ltd as Application Engineer

Aug 2014 to Sep 2015

Project Title R12 Customizations
Company GapBlue software Labs Pvt Ltd
Client School Specialty
Period Aug 2014 To Feb 2015
Description and Customization on Oracle iStore
Job Summary Part of programming java concurrent programs
MD20 Documentation and bug fix.
Technologies used Core Java, JSP, PL/SQL, java concurrent programs in oracle apps,
Angular JS, Redis, basic Unix
Role Application Engineer

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electronics/Telecommunication) from AWH ENGINEERING COLLEGE in 2010

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
SPRING BATCH	
CORE JAVA	
OAF, Oracle APEX, JavaScript	
Ajax, Jquery, Web Services	
Graph Databases (NEO4J, TITAN)	
Angular JS, bootstrap	
Angular 8, Node JS	
SQL, PL/SQL, Sybase, MYSQL	
Mongodb, SQLite	

Java 8, JSP, Java Servlets	
JMS, Spring Batch, Spring framework	
Quartz Job Scheduler	
WINDOWS, LINUX	
WinSCP, Putty, Kintana	
PVCS, Eclipse Oxygen	
NetBeans, Jdeveloper	
SoapUI 4.0	
Oracle SQL Developer	
Neo4j Community version	
Postman,Jenkins,MYSQL Workbench	
Visual Studio Code, Studio 3T	

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert			
Hindi				
Malayalam				

Affirmative Action

Category: General

Physically Challenged: No

Work Authorization

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time